CASILDA DE ZULUETA



contact@gatdesoia.es



TECHNICAL ART & ANIMATION

Based in Germany, with 7 years of experience in the games industry, and expertise in 3D art, technical art, animation, video editing, managing teams and teaching. Co-organizing the #FemDevsMeetup since 2018.

IN LOVE WITH THEORY AS MUCH AS WITH PRAXIS.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

3D ARTIST, TECHNICAL ARTIST, ANIMATOR

FREELANCER (RHO LABYRINTHS, SPOONDRIFT GAMES, FANTASTIC FOE, ACHTUNG AUTOBAHN, BRAINSEED FACTORY) | 2020 - PRESENT

Modelled and textured architecture modules, hard-surface props and stylized characters, following both PBR standards and alternative NPR solutions.

Rigged characters and props with custom skeletons and drivers. Animated characters for in-game actions and cutscene animation sequences.

Designed animation trees for gameplay interaction systems. Prepared animation controllers for logic implementation.

Documented and kept up-to-date development workflows for art and animation departments and set up guides for naming conventions and folder structures.

Lead art and animation teams (up to 3 people).

Wrote several custom shaders in HLSL and implemented those outsourced. Wrote simple tools in Unity Editor and Blender to automate art processes. (Projects: *Mars Vice, Dead Letters, Enclosed Encounter, Berlin Maniacs, The 7th Axe.*)

3D ARTIST, VIDEO EDITOR

FLYING SHEEP STUDIOS | 2017 - 2020

Modelled, textured, rigged and animated environments and characters for over 30 HTML5 titles, including licensed games for *Barbie, How to Train Your Dragon, Lego Ninjago, Trollhunters* and *Playmobil*.

Lead the character art team of 4 people for Knights of Fortune, prepared all rigs and animated half of the heroes.

Directed the art of Sunrise Roots. Prepared the base character rig and created all exterior buildings.

Managed the social media accounts, edited promotional videos and represented the company in several B2C and B2B conferences and fairs.

Documented best practices for 3D art and sound design for the company's internal tools.

ANIMATOR, CHARACTER DESIGNER, STORYBOARD

SUPERGLUE GAMES | 2016

Rigged and animated all characters from Moskito Beat, and designed two of its secondary characters.

Made the storyboard and CGI of the game's music clip.

SKILLS

SOFTWARE

Unity, Unreal Engine 5, Blender, Maya, Substance Painter, Spine, Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects & Premiere), Affinity Designer.

LANGUAGES

Proficiency in Spanish, Catalan & English. Mid level German.

AWARDS & NOMINATIONS

DEUTSCHER COMPUTERSPIELPREIS | 2023 Sonderpreis der Jury (#FemDevsMeetup)

DEUTSCHER ENTWICKLERPREIS | 2022

NRW-Förderpreis für junge Entwicklerinnen

DEUTSCHER ENTWICKLERPREIS | 2021

Nomination for *Berlin Maniacs* - Ubisoft Newcomer Award

IGDA FOUNDATION | 2021

Next Gen Leaders Program Recipient

GAMES 4 CHANGE EUROPE | 2014 Honorary Mention for *Pepper*

EDUCATION

COLOGNE GAME LAB | 2022

Game Development & Research M.A.

UNIVERSITAT POLITÈCNICA DE VALÈNCIA | 2015 Audiovisual Communication B.Soc.Sc.

TALKS, WORKSHOPS & LECTURES

WEGE IN DIE GAMESBRANCHE - 5 KURZVORTRÄGE

German Dev Days | 06-07/06/2023 - Frankfurt am Main, Germany

YOU ARE GOOD AT DRAWING, NOW WHAT? - THE TECHNICAL SKILLS OF A GAME ARTIST Baltic Dev Days | 01-02/06/2023 - Kiel, Germany

Universidad La Salle Noroeste | 04/04/2022 - Ciudad Obregón, Mexico

Games Industry. Uni Bayreuth | 02/02/2022 - Bayreuth, Germany

A VIRTUAL MEMORIAL FOR THE LACK OF PHYSICAL ONES

Interactive Pasts Conference 3 - VALUE Foundation | 24-26/05/2023 - Leiden, Netherlands

THE BLISS AND CURSE OF TURNING YOUR PASSION INTO YOUR SOURCE OF INCOME

Hamburg Games Conference | 01/03/2023 - Hamburg, Germany

#FemDevsMeetup V Mediennetzwer.NRW | 24/11/2022 - Düsseldorf, Germany

GAME DESIGN: THE PROTOTYPE

Universitat Politècnica de València | 02/02/2023 - Valencia, Spain

Hyper Talks. A MAZE | 17/05/2022 - Berlin, Germany

FUNDAMENTALS OF ANIMATION & ANIMATION TECHNIQUES (COURSE: 56H)

Hochschule Fresenius (Game Design & Management B.A.) | 2020 - 2022

BEYOND MOBILE: THE FUTURE OF HTML5 GAMES

Game Happens | 09/11/2019 - Genoa, Italy

Pocket Gamer Connects | 1-2/10/2019 - Helsinki, Finland

USING SPACE IN FILM & GAME GENRES

Womenize! Games and Film | 11/10/2019 - Cologne, Germany